Finding Aid for Inter-Cooperative Council (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records, 1932-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- House Records
  - Stevens (A.K. Stevens) House
    - House History
      - Undated (Box 17)
    - Photographs of demolition 1994 also CD-ROM, 2004, 1 optical disks CD-Rs (Box 17)
  - Trantor-Mir
    - House minutes
      - 1970 (Box 18)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 18)
    - House constitutions (Box 18)
    - House priority rules 1973 (Box 18)
    - House orientation letter 1981 (Box 18)
  - Truth (Sojourner Truth)
    - House Minutes-Renovation Committee 1988 (Box 18)
    - House Minutes
      - 1988-1989 (Box 18)
      - 1990-1996 (Box 18)
      - 2000-2007 (Box 18)
      - 2008-2009 (Box 18)
      - 2010 (Box 18)
    - House Constitution
      - 1990-1993 (Box 18)
      - 1995-1996 (Box 18)
    - House history (Box 18)
  - Vail (Stephan T. Vail)
    - House Minutes
      - October 1961-May 1966 (Box 18)
      - May 1967-October 1973 (Box 18)
      - January 1974-December 1975 (Box 18)
      - January 1976-November 1982 (Box 18)
      - January 1983-August 1987 (Box 18)
      - September 1987-October 1989 (Box 18)
      - 1992-1999 (Box 18)
      - 2005-2009 (Box 18)
    - House Constitution
      - 1958-1973 (Box 18)
      - 1984-1990 (Box 18)
      - Undated (Box 18)
    - House budget sheets 1975, 1977 (Box 18)
    - House history (Box 18)
  - Valhalla
    - House minutes
      - 1970 (Box 18)
      - 1974-1975, 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Walden III
    - House minutes and correspondence 1970 (Box 18)
    - House minutes and other materials 1976-1983 (Box 18)
    - House constitution and standing rules (Box 18)
  - Xanadu
    - House minutes
      - 1972-1983 (Box 18)
    - House constitution and policies 1972-1982 (Box 18)
    - Work description for clean-up, breakfast and lunch 1972 (Box 18)
    - Mixed materials
      - 1972-1982 (Box 18)
      - 1972-1986 (Box 18)
    - House Moving Documents Undated (Box 18)
    - House History/General Information Undated (Box 18)
    - House history, News articles (Box 18)
  - Zapata
    - House minutes 1970-1971 (Box 18)
  - Division Councils and Boarding Co-ops
    - Central Campus Division
      - Constitution 1969 (Box 38)
      - Constitution and regulations 1969-1977 (Box 38)
    - North Division Council
      - Meeting minutes 1982 (Box 38)
      - Restructuring committee minutes, reports, and other materials 1983-1984, 2 folders (Box 38)
      - Committee materials 1984 (Box 38)
      - Constitution 1972-1984 (Box 38)
      - Constitution and standing rules 1984 (Box 38)
    - South Campus Cooperative Division Council
      - Minutes 1976 (Box 38)
      - Constitution (Box 38)
      - Constitution, regulations, and memoranda 1972-1983 (Box 38)
    - Northwest Boarding Co-op
      - Policy board minutes 1983 (Box 38)
      - Constitution and standing rules 1980s (Box 38)
      - Mixed materials 1975-1995 (Box 38)
    - Southeast Boarding Co-op
      - Constitution and standing rules undated, 1983-1984 (Box 38)
      - Mixed materials 1970s, 1980s (Box 38)
  - Multiple Houses
    - Christmas cards (Box 38)
    - Legacy house lists, 3 folders (Box 38)
    - Loans made spring 1948 (Box 38)
    - Membership and financial records
      - 1938-1959, 3 folders (Box 38)
      - 1941-1951 (Box 38)
    - Membership/alumni lists 1939-1950 (Box 38)
    - Mixed materials 1970s, 1980s, 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Property maps with houses highlighted (Box 38)
  - Legal and Financial Documents
    - Abstract of Title
      - Michigan House 1961 (Box 33)
      - Minnie's House 1970 (Box 33)
      - Nakamura House 1970 (Box 33)
      - Mark VIII House 1961 (Box 33)
      - Osterweil House 1970 (Box 33)
      - Owen House 1961 (Box 33)
      - Pickerill House 1961 (Box 33)
      - Stevens House 1961 (Box 33)
      - Vail House 1961 (Box 33)
      - Lester House 1972 (Box 33)
      - King House 1961 (Box 33)
      - Debs House 1967 (Box 33)
    - Appraisals
      - 1975-1985 (Box 33)
      - 1985 1992 (Box 33)
      - 1988 (Box 33)
    - Loan applications
      - Various houses 1977, 2 folders (Box 33)
      - Various houses 1985 (Box 33)
      - Luther House 1986 (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Ownership histories and legal descriptions for houses (Box 33)
      - Xanadu deed and related correspondence 1978-1980 (Box 33)
      - Correspondence and notes regarding 1811 Washtenaw financial issues, 1988-1989 (Box 33)
      - Kagawa purchaser's closing statement 1990 (Box 33)
      - Luther house sales agreement 1985 (Box 33)
      - Gregory legal materials 1995 (Box 33)
      - Gregory closing papers 1995 (Box 33)
      - Gregory House property line divider dispute resolution 1996 (Box 33)
      - Vail and Xanadu mortgage location certificates (Box 33)
      - Mortgage surveys, 3 folders (Box 33)
- External Organizations
  The External Organizations series (1947-1998) includes correspondence, minutes, publications, reports, and other materials concerning organizations outside of the ICC. These organizations include the Fraternity Buyers' Association and its successor, the Student Buyers' Association, the Michigan Alliance of Cooperatives, the Campus Cooperative Development Corporations, the North American Students of Cooperation (NASCO), and many others. Materials are arranged alphabetically by organization name and then chronologically, with a folder of miscellaneous organizations and a directory of cooperatives placed at the end of the series.
  - Ann Arbor Cooperative Society 1948-1981 (Box 30)
  - Ann Arbor Mutual Housing Association 1995-1996 (Box 30)
  - Association of Cooperative Education/of Cooperative Educators
    - Membership handbook 1983 (Box 30)
    - Mixed materials 1966-1994, 4 folders (Box 30)
  - Campus Cooperative Development Corporation
    - Project narrative and other materials 1983-1991 (Box 30)
    - Development manual draft 1990 (Box 30)
    - Canadian Development Initiative 1991 (Box 30)
    - Meeting materials 1991 (Box 30)
    - By-laws and standing rules 1990 (Box 30)
    - Business plan 1990 (Box 30)
    - Meeting 1992 (Box 30)
    - Gauchi/CDF Proposals 1992 (Box 30)
    - Board meeting 1996 (Box 30)
    - NASCO properties 1989 (Box 30)
    - Project updates 1992 (Box 30)
    - Meeting 1990 (Box 30)
    - Mixed materials 1988-1991 (Box 30)
    - Contract 1987 (Box 30)
    - Meeting 1989 (Box 30)
  - Chicago Mutual Housing Network 1994 (Box 30)
  - Circle Pines Center (Delton, MI)
    - Mixed materials 1959-1989 (Box 30)
    - Pine Needles newsletter, 1971-1972 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence and other materials 1997-1998 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence and by-laws changes 1997-1998 (Box 30)
  - Co-op Auto (Ann Arbor, MI) 1975-1981 (Box 30)
  - Cooperative League of the United States America 1985 (Box 30)
  - Cooperative Services, Inc. (Detroit, MI)
    - The Cooperator newsletter, 1961-1975 (Box 30)
    - The Co-operator newspaper, 1974-1975 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence, brochures, and other materials 1969-1982 (Box 30)
    - Audit report 1971 (Box 30)
  - Davis Campus Cooperative 1989 (Box 30)
  - Federation of Southern Cooperatives 1993-1998 (Box 30)
  - Fellowship for International Community 1998 (Box 30)
  - Fraternity Buyers' Association
    - Mixed materials (including records of the 1959 decision to join the FBA), 1955-1969 (Box 30)
    - Mixed materials 1959-1969 (Box 30)
    - Mixed materials 1961-1966 (Box 30)
    - Mixed materials 1970-1971 (Box 30)
  - Grand Forks (ND) housing co-op recommendations & proposals 1997 (Box 31)
  - Japanese cooperative federations/associations 1995 (Box 31)
  - Ke-Kewya International/Muskegon Co-op 1996 (Box 31)
  - Latter Day Society of Equitable Pioneers; Rainbow Ridge 1985 (Box 31)
  - League of Renaissance Co-ops 1989 (Box 31)
  - Liberty Woods Senior Housing Cooperative (Spring Lake, MI) 1997 (Box 31)
  - Michigan Alliance of Cooperatives
    - Correspondence, reports, brochures 1979-1989 (Box 31)
    - Correspondence and reports 1986 (Box 31)
    - Mixed materials 1987-1996 (Box 31)
    - Video project and other materials 1989-1991 (Box 31)
    - Statewide organization revival effort 1992, 2 folders (Box 31)
    - Needs assessment survey 1994 (Box 31)
    - Annual meeting May 23, 1995 (Box 31)
    - Local networks (Box 31)
  - Michigan Association of Housing Cooperatives
    - Newsletters and other materials 1964-1972 (Box 31)
    - Correspondence, agendas, and minutes 1966-1973 (Box 31)
  - Michigan Federation of Food Co-ops 1974-1980 (Box 31)
  - Michigan Milling Cooperative 1997 (Box 31)
  - Michigan State University -- Student Housing Corporation
    - Articles of Incorporation circa 1977 (Box 31)
    - Code of Operations 1992 (Box 31)
    - Article 10 discussion and correspondence 1993, 1995 (Box 31)
    - Guide to Membership and code of operations circa 1996 (Box 31)
  - Midwest Association of Housing Co-operatives 1974-1979 (Box 31)
  - National Association of Collegiate Cooperatives 1995 (Box 31)
  - National Association of Housing Cooperatives
    - Publications and Citizens' Task Force materials 1991 (Box 31)
  - National College Student Credit Union Council 1995-1997 (Box 31)
  - National Cooperative Bank 1985-1989 (Box 31)
  - National Cooperative Business Association, Capital working group materials 1996 (Box 31)
  - National Rural Cooperative Development Task Force 1994 (Box 31)
  - North American Student Cooperative League 1947-1960 (Box 31)
  - North American Students of Cooperation (NASCO)
    - General materials 1971-1990, 5 folders (Box 32)
    - Minutes 1985-1987 (Box 32)
    - Financial information 1987 (Box 32)
    - Annual reports 1985, 1990 (Box 32)
    - NABSCO properties 1988 (Box 32)
  - People's Food Co-op (Ann Arbor, MI) 1974-1989 (Box 32)
  - Plunkett Foundation-Yearbook of Co-operative Enterprise 1990-1993 (Box 32)
  - Qumbya House #2 (Chicago) 1991 (Box 32)
  - Sister-city coops in Nicaragua 1986 (Box 32)
  - Student Buyers' Association
    - Agreements undated, 1997 (Box 32)
    - Meetings 1986-1987 (Box 32)
    - Financial information 1986-1987 (Box 32)
    - Personnel and committee materials 1987 (Box 32)
    - Meeting minutes, correspondence, and financial records 1971-1975 (Box 32)
    - Mixed materials 1975-1976 (Box 32)
    - Reports, meeting minutes, and correspondence 1977-1978 (Box 32)
    - Correspondence, newsletters, and other materials 1979 (Box 32)
    - Mixed materials 1979-1983 (Box 32)
    - Mixed materials 1983-1985 (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous co-ops, correspondence and other materials 1947-1951 (Box 32)
  - Directories, etc. of Michigan Co-ops 1973-1981 (Box 32)
- Audio-Visual Materials
  The Audio-Visual series (1937-2006) is divided into 7 subseries by format: Sound Recordings, Visual Recordings, Slides, Negatives, Prints, Photograph Albums, and Miscellaneous. Material include oral history interviews, documentaries about ICC and other cooperative organizations, and photographic images (slides, negatives, or prints) of ICC events, people and houses. The Slides, Negatives, and Prints subseries are arranged chronologically. The Photograph Albums subseries is arranged by the title or subject of the albums. Many albums contained loose photographs as well as album pages; these have been grouped according to their original arrangement in binder.
  - Sound recordings (Box 19)
    - Sound recording re. history of ICC 1972, 5 inch reels; 3 3/4 ips (Box 19)
    - Audio-cassettes of interviews 1970s-1980s, 17 audiocassettes (Box 19)
    - Audio-cassettes: Muriel Lester 50th anniversary, 2 audiocassettes (Box 19)
    - Audio-cassette: Karl Gregory speaking at the CORE 50 year reunion near Chicago October 1999 (Box 19)
  - Video recordings
    - Videotapes (VHS) of interviews and programs in connection with the 50th anniversary celebration of ICC 1994, 12 audiocassettes (Box 19)
    - Videotape (VHS) "Working together: The Story of the ICC" September 1994, 27:25 (Box 19)
    - Videotape (VHS) October 1, 1994 President's Breakfast and Oral history (Box 19)
    - Videotape (VHS), "Working Together: The Story of the ICC," August 31, 1994 (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), Democracy in the Workplace: Three Worker-Owned Businesses in Action" (Off Center Video) (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "The ABC's of Cooperative Childcare," UC Regents 1996 (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "History of C.S.I. & Housing Co-ops -- Wyandotte Interview with Fred & Virginia Thornwaite" (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "National Productions: The Cooperative Story" (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "Workers' Own," Worker Ownership Development Foundation (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "How to Start a Cooperative Food Buying Club," National Cooperative Business Association 1993 (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "The Mondragon Experiment," Films Incorporated (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "They can cut all the flowers, but they will never stop the spring," Seven Generations Video, The Ben Linder Memorial Fund for Appropriate Technology (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "Our Journey of Honor: 442nd Veterans Club 50th Golden Anniversary" (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "Welcome to the ICC" (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "The Spirit of Cooperation: The story of cooperatives and how Americans use them to improve their lives and communities," National Tele-Productions 1994 (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "Dream Tower: A film by Ron Mann," National Film Board of Canada 1994 (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "The tour thru Ruths" (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "Newsclip from the ICC Alternative Spring Break in Chicago," ChicagoLand TV 1994 (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "Working Together: The Story of the ICC" (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "Co-op Board Leadership Training: Michigan Alliance of Cooperatives with Arrowwood, Pine Lake Village, and Forest Hills Housing Cooperatives," 1990 (3 tapes) (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "Cooperative Voices," Michigan Alliance of Cooperatives 1989 (Box 44)
    - Videotape (VHS), "Cooperative Voices," Michigan Alliance of Cooperatives April 5, 1989 (Box 44)
  - Slides (Box 20)
    - House meetings, house exteriors, and co-op members 1948-1950, 1987 (Box 20)
    - Luther Day Celebration 1976 (Box 20)
    - 50th Anniversary celebration 1987 (Box 20)
    - Houses (exterior) (Box 20)
    - House (interior) (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 20)
  - Negatives
    - Unlabeled circa 1990s, 7 folders (Box 20)
    - Joint, Stevens (#7), unlabeled circa 1990s (Box 20)
    - Truth (#8, #9), Joint (#5) circa 1990s (Box 20)
    - Vail (#5), Linder (#11) circa 1990s (Box 20)
    - Luther basketball 1993 (Box 20)
    - Unlabeled 1993 (Box 20)
    - NASCO Institute, MCAC Committee, and Vail Murals 1997 (Box 20)
    - Winter Annual Meeting (WAM) and Summer Education 1998 (Box 20)
    - Winter Annual Meeting (WAM) 1999 (Box 20)
      (with index print)
    - New Member Orientation, Board of Directors training, Board of Directors meeting, Cooperator staff, ombudsperson, ... 1999 (Box 20)
    - Unlabeled circa 2000 (Box 20)
    - Unlabeled 2000 (Box 20)
    - Summer education field trip 2000 (Box 20)
    - Unlabeled 2001 (Box 20)
    - Truck logo, Bonnie's goodbye, Board of Directors retreat 2003 (Box 20)
    - Unlabeled 2004 (Box 20)
    - Black and white undated, 4 folders (Box 20)
  - Prints
    - Miscellaneous contact sheets 1969-1980 (Box 20)
    - Several ICC presidents, late 1980s (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous groups and individuals 1993-2006 (Box 20)
    - Summer 2002 (Box 20)
  - Photograph albums
    - Untitled (showcasing individual houses) circa 1995 (Volume 1)
    - Welcome home (showcasing individual houses), circa 1997 (Volume 2)
    - Untitled (snapshots of ICC houses and daily activities) 1970s (Box 27)
    - 'Past houses'
      - Loose photographs, 4 folders (Box 27)
      - Album pages 1942-1991, 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Black Elk
      - Loose photographs (Box 27)
      - Album pages 1993-1997 (Box 27)
    - Debs
      - Loose photographs (Box 27)
      - Album pages 1967-1994 (Box 27)
    - Gregory
      - Loose photographs (Box 27)
      - Album pages 1995 (Box 27)
    - Joint
      - Loose photographs (Box 27)
      - Album pages 1967-1993, 3 folders (Box 27)
    - King/Brandeis
      - Loose photographs (Box 27)
      - Album pages, undated-1993 (Box 27)
    - Lester
      - Album pages 1942-1997, 2 folders (Box 27)
      - Loose photographs (Box 27)
    - Linder
      - Loose photographs (Box 27)
      - Album pages circa 1994 (Box 27)
    - Luther/Education Center
      - Loose photographs, 2 folders (Box 27)
      - Album pages 1975-1999 (Box 27)
    - Michigan, #1
      - Loose photographs, 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Album pages 1937-1993, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Michigan, #2
      - Loose photographs, 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Album pages 1988-1998, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Minnie's
      - Album pages 1980, undated (Box 28)
      - Loose photographs (Box 28)
    - Nakamura (and some Kagawa and Black Elk)
      - Loose photographs, 3 folders (Box 28)
      - Album pages 1950-1994, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - North Campus
      - Loose photographs, 3 folders (Box 28)
      - Album pages 1969-1998 (Box 28)
    - Osterweil
      - Loose photographs, 3 folders (Box 28)
      - Album pages 1950s-1990 (Box 28)
    - Owen
      - Loose photographs, 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Album pages 1944-1988, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Rochdale Center
      - Loose photographs (Box 29)
      - Album pages 1995-1999 (Box 29)
    - Ruths'
      - Loose photographs, 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Album pages undated, 1994 (Box 29)
    - Stevens album 1990s (Box 29)
    - Stevens
      - Loose photographs (Box 29)
      - Album pages 1943-1998, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Truth/Bruce
      - Loose photographs (Box 29)
      - Album pages 1977-1993, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Vail
      - Loose photographs (Box 29)
      - Album pages, late 1970s-1997, 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Photographs and slides of Owen House members and activities 1948-1952, 2 folders; 1 oversize volumes (Box 29)
      (collected by David L. Smith)
    - Promotional and other visual materials, 4 folders (Box 29)
    - Cooperatives Learning Modules 1-4, Quentin Burdick Center for Cooperatives, Fargo, North Dakota (CD-ROM) (Box 44)